{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "which is the most popular javascript framework ?",
      "options": ["Angular", "React", "Svelte", "Vue"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },


    {
      "question": "Which company invented React ?",
      "options": ["Google", "Apple", "Netflix", "Facebook"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },

    {
      "question": "what's the fundamental building block of React apps ?",
      "options": ["Components", "Blocks", "Elements", "Effects"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },

    {
      "question": "What's the name of the syntax we use to describe the ui In React Components ?",
      "options": ["FBJ", "Babel", "JSX", "ES2015"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },

    {
      "question": "How does data flow naturally in React apps ?",
      "options": [
        "From parents to children",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "the developers decide"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },

    {
      "question": "How does data flow naturally in React apps ?",
      "options": [
        "From parents to children",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "the developers decide"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "How to pass data into a child component ?",
      "options": ["State", "Props", "PropTypes", "Parametres"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },

    {
      "question": "When to use derived state ?",
      "options": [
        "Whenever the State should not trigger a re-render",
        "Whenever the State can be synchronized with an effect",

        "Whenever  the state should be accessible to all comonenets",
        "Whenever the State can be computed from another state variable"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },

    {
      "question": "What triggers a Ui re-render In React?",
      "options": [
        "Running an effect",
        "passing props",
        "updating state",
        "Adding event listners to Dom elements"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "When do we directly touch the Dom in React ? ",
      "options": [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the Ui",
        "when we need to add styles",
        "Almost never"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },

    {
      "question": "When do we directly touch the Dom in React ? ",
      "options": [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the Ui",
        "when we need to add styles",
        "Almost never"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },

    {
      "question": "In what situation do we use a callback to update state ?  ",
      "options": [
        "when updtating the state will be slow",
        "when the update state is very data-intensive",
        "when the state update should happen faster",
        "when the new state depends on the previous state"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },

    {
      "question": " if we pass a function to useState , when will tha function be called ? ",
      "options": [
        "On each re-render",
        "Each time we update the state",
        "Only on the initial render ",
        "The first time we update the state"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    } ,

        {
      "question": " Which hook to use for an API request on the component's initial render ",
      "options": [
       "useState" , "useEffect" , "useRef" , "useReducer"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    } ,

            {
      "question": " which variables should go into the useEffect dependency array ? ",
      "options": [
        "Usually none" , 
        "All our state variables" , 
        "All state and props referenced in the effect" , 
        "All variables nedded clean up"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    } ,

    

                {
      "question": " An Effect will always run on the initial render ?  ",
      "options": [
        "True" , 
        "it depends on the dependency array" , 
        "False" , 
        "In depends on the code in the effect"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    } ,

                    {
      "question": " when will an effect run if doesn't have a dependency array ? ",
      "options": [
       "Only when the component amounts" ,
       "Only when the component unmounts" , 
       "The first time the component re-render" , 
       "Each time the component is re-render"


      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    } 
  ]
}
